RG 074:013, Duane N. Griffin Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Duane N. Griffin genealogical papers
1723-1951
bulk circa 1900-1927
Connecticut State Library
Griffin, Duane N
.75 cubic feet
Rev. Duane N. Griffin (1853-1927) was a Hartford area Methodist minister. These papers consist of a manuscript genealogy of the descendents of John Griffin of Simsbury, Conn. and genealogy notes on the Griffin Family.
RG074_013
1927-020
Biographical Note
Duane N. Griffin was born in Granby, Conn. on December 4, 1853 to Richardson Griffin and Julia Ann (Viets) Griffin. He married Ada Belle Moore. They had a son, Ray Maynard Griffin and a daughter, Janice Griffin. He died at his home in Granby on November 8, 1927.
In 1882, Griffin became pastor of the Unionville Methodist Church and later the Plainville Methodist Church. He went on to graduate in theology from Boston University. He returned to his ministerial work and became pastor at Trinity Methodist Church in Meriden, then the Hamden Methodist Church, Epworth Methodist Church in New Haven, the North Methodist Church in Hartford, and St. Andrew's Methodist Church in New Haven.
While at St. Andrew's, Griffin was appointed field secretary of the Connecticut prohibition committee and held that position for fifteen years. During this time he also served as associate pastor of South park Methodist Church in Hartford. He retired from active church work in 1913 but became supply pastor for the Copper Hill Methodist Church in Granby. He retired in 1926.
Griffin also was a candidate for governor, mayor of Hartford and senator-at-large on the Prohibition ticket. He also served as editor for a prohibition publication.
Source: "Rev. D.N. Griffin, Former Hartford Minister Dies." Hartford Courant, 1927 November 10, 2.
Scope and Content
These papers consist of a manuscript genealogy of the descendents of John Griffin of Simsbury, Conn. and genealogy notes.
Related Material
Griffin, Griffing family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1917-1995
Giffin, Griffin family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1963
Index Terms
Persons:
Griffin, Duane N
Family Names:
Griffin family
Places:
Simsbury (Conn.) -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Correspondence; Genealogies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Folders 1-13 were presented by Miss Janice M. Griffin of Granby, Conn. on December 17, 1927.
Folder 14 was presented by Miss Janice M. Griffin on February 6, 1947.
Folder 15 was a gift from George Mitchelson of North Bloomfield, Ct.
Map of Cardiganshire, Wales and the pamphlet of the Cathedral Church of St. David: a handbook, both in folder 6, were received on March 25, 1952 from Miss Janice M. Griffin, from London, England.
Container List
- Papers, 1723, 1870, 1900-1927, 1947-1951, undated; bulk circa 1900-1927
  - List of contents, 1927 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inventory by Mrs. B.M. Dewey, 1971 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Griffins - "History of Redding, Conn." by Charles Burr Todd, circa 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family of Susan Griffin, daughter of Azel Griffin, married Hiram J. Waters (probably Simsbury), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hand-written genealogy compiled by Rev. Duane N. Griffin, descendants of John Griffin of Simsbury, Conn. (Part 1, pp. 1-100), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hand-written genealogy compiled by Rev. Duane N. Griffin, descendants of John Griffin of Simsbury, Conn. (Part 2, pp. 101-199), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hand-written genealogy compiled by Rev. Duane N. Griffin, descendants of John Griffin of Simsbury, Conn. (Part 3, pp. 200-265), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Hampton, Conn. Griffins, descendants of Richard Griffin, notes from Vol. II History of Windham Co., Conn., undated; 20 sheets (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes by Rev. Duane N. Griffin.
  - Families of Griffins who married Holcombs from the record of Amasa Holcomb of Southwick, Mass., undated; 8 sheets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hugh Griffin of Stratford, undated; 3 sheets (Box 1, Folder 6)
    His will dated September 9, 1690, some of his descendants, other Griffins.
  - Ebenezer Griffin, Hampton, undated; 25 sheets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jonathan Giliet line of Windsor, Conn. and descendants, undated; 39 sheets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Sgt. John Griffin, Simsbury, inventory, undated; 4 sheets (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes on genealogy, undated; 7 sheets and fragments (Box 1, Folder 7)
    See also folder 8.
  - I.W. Griffin, Battle Greek, Mich. to Mrs. M. Hatch, Columbia, N.Y. on Martin IV Griffin, grandfather of I.W. Griffin, 1900, undated; 2 letters (6 sheets) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - On Welsh pedigree of Edward Griffin of Flushing, N.Y. by Mr. Zeno T. Griffin, Chicago, Ill., a descendant of Edward I, undated; 6 sheets (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Map of England and Wales, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Cathedral Church of St. David: A handbook, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - George S. Godard to Duane N. Griffin on photostat of early Simsbury, Conn. map, circa 1730, 1916 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Photostat map of early Simsbury, Conn. is not present.
  - 1790 - First U.S. Census of Connecticut - lists Griffin in Conn. towns, undated; 3 sheets (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut military records for Griffins, 1775-1848, undated; 1 sheet + 1 fragment (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sgt. John Griffin and first three generations by Rev. Mr. Griffin, undated; Typed with hand-written additions, 4 sheets (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reunion of the children and descendants of Zopher and Margaret Griffin of Granby, Conn., deceased, held at their late residence, 1870 September 14; 1 printed poster (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Lists people present with town and state including 8 children, 20 grandchildren, 10 great-grandchildren, and two couples of friends.
  - A Corner in ancestors - Griffin, Waterbury Republican (Conn.), 1911 November 26; 1 newspaper clipping (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charles Griffin, Major General, U.S. Army, born 1826 died 1867, 2 fragments (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Typed from History of Licking Co. Ohio, 1881
    From Zeno T. Griffin to Rev. Duane N. Griffin
  - Notice for Griffen - Griffin genealogy, descendants of Edward Griffin, 1602-1698, by Josephine C. Frost, 1 item (subscription blank separated from notice) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Welsh dates and pedigree by Zeno T. Griffin, undated; 23 sheets and fragments (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - J.D. Reed, lawyer, Richfield, Springs, NY - to Stanley C. Griffin, Columbus Ohio, on Peter Griffin, no heirs, grandson of Martin Griffin, the elder and son of Oliver (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter from John Carlisle Griffin and other notes, 1914, undated; 7 sheets (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters received by Rev. Duane N. Griffin (Box 1)
    Letters are in numerical order.
    Some numbers contain multiple letters.
    - Numbers 1-12, 1914-1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Numbers 13-42, 1900-1925, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Numbers 43-61, unnumbered material, 1900-1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notes made by Zeno T. Grffin, Chicago, Ill., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Zeno T. Griffin co-worked with Duane N. Griffin on the Griffin genealogy. He copied much of this material from books in the Newberry Library, Chicago.
    - Probate records of Conn. Hartford District by Manwaring (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Simsbury probate records (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hartford County memorial history, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified items (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1916-1924, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Letters of Zeno T. Griffin of Chocago, Ill. written to Rev. Duane N. Griffin of Granby, Conn., 1914-1917 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    In numerical order 1-46. There is no number 18 or 28.
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1927, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Petition by Simsbury men to the General Assembly, 1723; photostat (Box 2, Folder 16)